Guide to the G. Fred Blackburn papers, 1850-1993 MS2161
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
G. Fred Blackburn papers
1850-1993
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS2161
0.5 Linear Feet
Collection contains photographs, newspaper clippings, newsletters, correspondence, and other materials related to the C&O Canal, the hike of 1954, and subsequent reunion hikes. The materials date from 1850-1993.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Historical or Biographical Note
George Frederick Blackburn (1903-1990) was an active member of the Potomac Appalachian Trail Club (PATC), serving as its president between 1951 and 1955. Blackburn was born in Cessna, Pennsylvania in 1903, and received Bachelor and Masters degrees in Mathematics from Princeton University. He relocated to the Washington, D.C. area and worked for the National Bureau of Standards for the majority of his career. Blackburn joined the PATC in 1929, and became actively involved in its activities in the 1930s and 1940s. He served as the organization's president for four years, beginning in 1951. Under his leadership, the PATC fought efforts to convert the Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Towpath into a scenic highway. Blackburn was a participant in the hike led by Justice William O. Douglas in 1954 to draw attention to the scenic beauty of the canal, as well as subsequent reunion hikes. G. Fred Blackburn died in 1990.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains photographs, newspaper clippings, newsletters, correspondence, and other materials related to the C&O Canal, the hike of 1954, and subsequent reunion hikes. The materials date from 1850-1993.
Chesapeake and Ohio Canal (Md. and Washington, D.C.); Photographs; Blackburn, George Frederick
- Biography, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- C & O Canal, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- C & O Canal Association, 1970-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- C & O Canal Association Annual Reunion Hike, 1963-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- C & O Canal Association Annual Reunion Hike -- Towpath Notes, 1957-1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- C & O Canal Hike, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Congressional Record -- Development of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal National Historical Park, 12/22/1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1958-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Hiking songs, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Lists of names, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Minutes of National Capital Wilderness Study Committee, 04/28/1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Newsletters and pamphlets, 1950-1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Newspaper clippings, 1850-1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- PATC hikes, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Petition to establish C & O Canal National Park, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Photographs, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Potomac National River proposal, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Slides, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 19)